<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--

       Copyright 2010-2026 the original author or authors.

       Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
       you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
       You may obtain a copy of the License at

          https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

       Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
       distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
       WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
       See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
       limitations under the License.

-->
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

  <properties>
    <title>MyBatis-Spring | Sample Code</title>
    <author email="eduardo.macarron@gmail.com">Eduardo Macarron</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Sample Code">
      <p>
      	JPetStore 6 is a full web application built on top of MyBatis 3,
      	<a href="http://projects.spring.io/spring-framework/">Spring 6</a> and
      	<a href="https://spring.io/projects/spring-framework">Spring Web MVC</a>.
        It is available for download in the
        <a href="https://github.com/mybatis/jpetstore-6/releases">downloads</a>
        section of MyBatis project site.
        In this section we will walk through this sample to understand how is it built and learn how to run it.
      </p>

      <subsection name="Translations">
        <p>Users can read this doc in following translations:</p>
        <ul class="i18n">
          <li class="es"><a href="./es/index.html">Español</a></li>
          <li class="ja"><a href="./ja/index.html">日本語</a></li>
          <li class="ko"><a href="./ko/index.html">한국어</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Do you want to read about MyBatis in your own native language? File an issue providing patches with your
        mother tongue documentation!</p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Purpose">
      	<p>
      	This new JPetStore comes with the same idea in mind than its predecessors: <strong>keep it simple</strong>.
      	The purpose of JPetStore 6 is to demonstrate how to build a web application with very few classes and no advanced coding skills.
      	You just need to know plain Java and SQL.
      	</p>
      	<p>
      	The 6th version of JPetStore is the smallest of the family, 20% smaller than its predecessor.
      	It uses just 24 java classes while keeping a good design and program structure.
      	</p>
      	<pre>
eduardo@nomada ~ $ ./cloc-1.60.pl ~/git/jpetstore-6/src/main/
      60 text files.
      60 unique files.
       3 files ignored.

http://cloc.sourceforge.net v 1.60  T=0.28 s (209.8 files/s, 17722.9 lines/s)
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Language                     files          blank        comment           code
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Java                            24            480            462           1429
JSP                             20            148              0            984
XML                              9             79            120            405
CSS                              1             46              0            277
SQL                              2             26             30            226
HTML                             2             44              0            143
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
SUM:                            58            823            612           3464
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
      	</pre>
      	<p>
      	As we will see later on, you will find no code to deal with JDBC, to create objects or bind them or to handle transactions.
      	What is more impressive is that you <strong>will not find any call to the MyBatis API</strong>.
      	Although this sounds magical, you will see that the combination of MyBatis mappers and dependency injection lets you
      	build applications without dependencies.
      	</p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Program Structure">
      	<p> JPetStore 6 follows the typical maven project structure </p>
<pre>/jpetstore                    <tt>&lt;-- Maven pom.xml goes here.</tt>
  /src
    /main
      /java                   <tt>&lt;-- Java code goes here.</tt>
        /org
          /mybatis
            /jpetstore
              /domain         <tt>&lt;-- Business domain objects go here.</tt>
              /mapper         <tt>&lt;-- Mapper interfaces go here.</tt>
              /service        <tt>&lt;-- Application logic goes here.</tt>
              /web
                /controllers  <tt>&lt;-- Presentation logic (controllers) goes here.</tt>
      /resources              <tt>&lt;-- Non java files go here.</tt>
        /org
          /mybatis
            /jpetstore
              /mapper         <tt>&lt;-- Mapper XML files go here.</tt>
        /database
      /webapp
        /css
        /images
        /WEB-INF              <tt>&lt;-- web.xml and applicationContext.xml go here.</tt>
          /jsp                <tt>&lt;-- JSP files go here.</tt>
      </pre>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Configuration files">
      <p>
      Configuration files are read during application startup. Their purpose is to configure the
      frameworks composing the application: Spring Web MVC and MyBatis. We will need to configure
      three files: web.xml, spring-mvc.xml and applicationContext.xml.
      </p>
      <h4>web.xml</h4>
      <p>
      We configure Spring's DispatcherServlet which serves as the front controller for all HTTP requests:
      </p>
<source><![CDATA[
<servlet>
  <servlet-name>dispatcher</servlet-name>
  <servlet-class>org.springframework.web.servlet.DispatcherServlet</servlet-class>
  <init-param>
    <param-name>contextConfigLocation</param-name>
    <param-value>/WEB-INF/spring-mvc.xml</param-value>
  </init-param>
  <load-on-startup>1</load-on-startup>
</servlet>
<servlet-mapping>
  <servlet-name>dispatcher</servlet-name>
  <url-pattern>/</url-pattern>
</servlet-mapping>
]]></source>

	<p>We also add a Spring context listener to load the root application context (applicationContext.xml):</p>

<source><![CDATA[
<listener>
  <listener-class>org.springframework.web.context.ContextLoaderListener</listener-class>
</listener>
]]></source>

      <h4>spring-mvc.xml</h4>
      <p>
      This file configures Spring Web MVC. It enables annotation-driven MVC, configures the
      component scan for controllers, and sets up the JSP view resolver:
      </p>
<source><![CDATA[
<mvc:annotation-driven />
<mvc:default-servlet-handler />

<context:component-scan base-package="org.mybatis.jpetstore.web.controllers" />

<bean class="org.springframework.web.servlet.view.InternalResourceViewResolver">
  <property name="prefix" value="/WEB-INF/jsp/" />
  <property name="suffix" value=".jsp" />
</bean>
]]></source>

      <h4>applicationContext.xml</h4>
      <p>As you already know, applicationContext.xml is the Spring's configuration file. Spring is a dependency
      injection framework and it has to know which beans it must create and how to bind them together and that is
      what applicationContext.xml file is for. Let's have a deeper look into it.
      </p>
      <p>
      The first and easiest thing we have to do is let Spring know where are our service beans. We will let Spring
      search them in our classpath so we just need to provide it the base package to search in:
      </p>

<source><![CDATA[
<context:component-scan base-package="org.mybatis.jpetstore.service" />
]]></source>

	  <p>
	  <span class="label important">NOTE</span> Spring's component scan feature is not able to find MyBatis mappers.
	  A mapper is not a plain bean and Spring would not know how to instantiate it. We will see how to search for mappers soon.
	  </p>

	  <p>We will also need a <code>DataSource</code> and a <code>TransactionManager</code>. Given that this is a demo application
	  we will use a test Spring <code>DataSource</code> that will create an HSQL in-memory database and load
	  our database scripts into it and the standard Spring's <code>DataSourceTransactionManager</code>
	  to handle transactions.
	  </p>

<source><![CDATA[
<jdbc:embedded-database id="dataSource">
  <jdbc:script location="classpath:database/jpetstore-hsqldb-schema.sql"/>
  <jdbc:script location="classpath:database/jpetstore-hsqldb-dataload.sql"/>
</jdbc:embedded-database>

<bean id="transactionManager" class="org.springframework.jdbc.datasource.DataSourceTransactionManager">
  <property name="dataSource" ref="dataSource" />
</bean>
]]></source>

	  <p>
	  So far, all we have done is standard Spring MVC and Spring configuration and now it is time to
	  move on to the MyBatis part. As you have learned in this manual to set up MyBatis with Spring you need
	  at least two things: an <code>SqlSessionFactoryBean</code> and, at least, one mapper class.
	  So let's go hands on. First define a <code>SqlSessionFactoryBean</code>:
	  </p>

<source><![CDATA[
<bean id="sqlSessionFactory" class="org.mybatis.spring.SqlSessionFactoryBean">
  <property name="dataSource" ref="dataSource" />
</bean>
]]></source>

      <p>And now we need to setup our mappers. For that purpose we will use the <code>MapperScannerConfigurer</code>
      that works similar to Spring standard component scan. It will search our classpath for mapper classes
      and register them to MyBatis. Similar to Spring's component scan we must configure the base
      package to search in.
      </p>

<source><![CDATA[
<mybatis:scan base-package="org.mybatis.jpetstore.mapper" />
]]></source>

      <p>To save some writing when building our mapper xml files we would want to be able to use short
      aliases for beans. The <code>SqlSessionFactoryBean</code> has the capability to search for beans and
      register their short names as aliases if we setup the <code>typeAliasPackage</code> property like
      the following:
      </p>

<source><![CDATA[
<bean id="sqlSessionFactory" class="org.mybatis.spring.SqlSessionFactoryBean">
  <property name="dataSource" ref="dataSource" />
  <property name="typeAliasesPackage" value="org.mybatis.jpetstore.domain" />
</bean>
]]></source>

		<p>Our application is now fully configured and ready to run. But before running it lets have a tour
		through the code to see how it looks like.
		</p>

      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Code tour">
      <p>JPetStore 6 is a typical MVC application with three layers: presentation, logic and data access.
      </p>
      <h4>Presentation</h4>
      <p>The presentation layer is composed by JSP files and Spring MVC Controllers. JSPs just use plain HTML,
      JSTL tags and standard form elements. Spring MVC Controllers handle HTTP requests and populate the model
      for the views.
      </p>
      <p>Given that our controllers are Spring-managed, we can inject our services directly using
      standard Spring dependency injection. Have a look at <code>CatalogController</code>:
      </p>

<source><![CDATA[
@Controller
@RequestMapping("/catalog")
public class CatalogController {
  ...
  @Autowired
  private CatalogService catalogService;
  ...
  @GetMapping("/viewCategory")
  public String viewCategory(@RequestParam(value = "categoryId", required = false) String categoryId, Model model) {
    if (categoryId != null) {
      model.addAttribute("productList", catalogService.getProductListByCategory(categoryId));
      model.addAttribute("category", catalogService.getCategory(categoryId));
    }
    return "catalog/Category";
  }
  ...
]]></source>

      <h4>Logic</h4>
      <p>Application logic is composed by plain Java beans that act as services and plain Java beans that
      act as domain objects. This layer is in charge of filling domain objects with database data and
      updating database data with the content of the domain objects. For this purpose this layer must be
      transactional.
      </p>
      <p>Let's have a look at <code>OrderService</code> code to see how all this is achieved:
      </p>

<source><![CDATA[
@Service
public class OrderService {

  @Autowired
  private ItemMapper itemMapper;
  @Autowired
  private OrderMapper orderMapper;
  @Autowired
  private LineItemMapper lineItemMapper;

  @Transactional
  public void insertOrder(Order order) {
    order.setOrderId(getNextId("ordernum"));
    for (int i = 0; i < order.getLineItems().size(); i++) {
      LineItem lineItem = (LineItem) order.getLineItems().get(i);
      String itemId = lineItem.getItemId();
      Integer increment = new Integer(lineItem.getQuantity());
      Map<String, Object> param = new HashMap<String, Object>(2);
      param.put("itemId", itemId);
      param.put("increment", increment);
      itemMapper.updateInventoryQuantity(param);
    }

    orderMapper.insertOrder(order);
    orderMapper.insertOrderStatus(order);
    for (int i = 0; i < order.getLineItems().size(); i++) {
      LineItem lineItem = (LineItem) order.getLineItems().get(i);
      lineItem.setOrderId(order.getOrderId());
      lineItemMapper.insertLineItem(lineItem);
    }
  }
]]></source>

      <p>The first thing you will notice is that there is no JDBC code in the service,
      nor it is any MyBatis code in it. You may think that we used the
      DAO pattern and database access code is in the database layer, but as we will see later,
      the database layer is built with MyBatis mappers, that are plain java
      interfaces, and that is why <strong>you will not find any call to MyBatis API</strong>
      in the whole application. It is just not needed.</p>

      <p>The second thing you may have noticed is that there are no commits or rollbacks.
      That is because it uses the declarative transaction demarcation feature of Spring that is
      fully supported by MyBatis-Spring.
      The Spring's <code>@Transactional</code> annotation indicates that this method is transactional,
      that means that all <code>updateInventoryQuantity</code>, <code>insertOrder</code> and
      <code>insertLineItem</code> mapper calls must end OK. If one of them fails any previous
      update will be rolled back.</p>

      <h4>Persistence</h4>
      <p>The persistence layer is composed of MyBatis mappers. Mappers are just plain Java
      interfaces and mapper XML files containing the SQL statements.
      There is no custom Java code in this layer. When the
      <code>getOrder</code> method is called on the <code>OrderMapper</code> interface,
      MyBatis will execute the getOrder SQL statement in OrderMapper.xml file and
      will populate the <code>Order</code> domain bean with retrieved data.
      </p>

<source><![CDATA[
public interface OrderMapper {
  List<Order> getOrdersByUsername(String username);
  Order getOrder(int orderId);
  void insertOrder(Order order);
  void insertOrderStatus(Order order);
}]]></source>

<source><![CDATA[
<mapper namespace="org.mybatis.jpetstore.mapper.OrderMapper">

  <cache />

  <select id="getOrder" resultType="Order">
    SELECT
      BILLADDR1 AS billAddress1,
      BILLADDR2 AS billAddress2,
      BILLCITY,
      BILLCOUNTRY,
      BILLSTATE,
      BILLTOFIRSTNAME,
      BILLTOLASTNAME,
      BILLZIP,
      SHIPADDR1 AS shipAddress1,
      SHIPADDR2 AS shipAddress2,
      SHIPCITY,
      SHIPCOUNTRY,
      SHIPSTATE,
      SHIPTOFIRSTNAME,
      SHIPTOLASTNAME,
      SHIPZIP,
      CARDTYPE,
      COURIER,
      CREDITCARD,
      EXPRDATE AS expiryDate,
      LOCALE,
      ORDERDATE,
      ORDERS.ORDERID,
      TOTALPRICE,
      USERID AS username,
      STATUS
    FROM ORDERS, ORDERSTATUS
    WHERE ORDERS.ORDERID = #{value}
      AND ORDERS.ORDERID = ORDERSTATUS.ORDERID
  </select>
  ...
</mapper>
]]></source>

      <p>
      <span class="label important">NOTE</span>
      You can easily add caching to your queries by adding a &lt;cache /&gt; element to your mapper xml file.
      </p>

      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Running JPetStore">
        <p>You may ask. Does all this work? Yes it does! Let's run it.</p>
        <p>Let's assume you have a clean computer. These are the steps you should follow to
           have the sample running under Tomcat:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>See <a href="https://github.com/mybatis/jpetstore-6#running-with-tomcat" target="how-to-run">here</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>
          Now you are ready to play with it, experiment with your own changes or whatever you want.
        </p>
        <p>
          And remember that if you find a bug or something that is missing or can be improved (for example the missing tests!),
          fork the repo, change it, and open a pull request. Thanks in advance!!!
        </p>
        <p>
        <span class="label important">NOTE</span>
		JPetStore 6 requires a Servlet 6.0 / JSP 3.1 compliant Java server (e.g., Tomcat 10.1+).
        </p>
      </subsection>

    </section>
  </body>
</document>
